■
字幕来源：九洲客    后期：Sung1219
本字幕非人人影视翻译  人人影视只做压制处理
片名  剪刀手爱德华
外面很冷  快钻进被窝
Snuggle in, sweetie! lt's cold out there.
为什么会下雪? 雪是从哪里来的?
Why is it snowing, Grandma? Where does it come from?
这说来话长
Oh, that's a long story, sweetheart.
-我想听  -改天再说  快睡吧
-I wanna hear. -Oh, not tonight. Go to sleep.
我还不困  告诉我吧  求求你
I'm not sleepy. Tell me, please.
好吧
Well, all right.
我来想想
Let's see...
我想就从剪刀说起吧
I guess it would have to start with... scissors!
剪刀?
Scissors?
什么的剪刀都有
Well, there are all kinds of scissors.
从前  有个人的手便是剪刀
And once there was even a man who had scissors for hands.
-男人? -是
-A man? -Yes.
-手拿剪刀? -不  是剪刀手
-Hands scissors? -No, scissor hands.
你知道山顶那座古堡吗?
You know the mansion on top of the mountain?
那里在闹鬼
It's haunted.
嗯
Well...
很久以前
A long time ago...
有位发明家住在那里
an inventor lived in that mansion.
他发明了许多东西
He made many things, I suppose.
他甚至创造出一个人
He also created a man.
他给他造了器官  心脏  头脑  以及一切
He gave him insides, a heart, a brain, everything.
几乎什么都有了
Well, almost everything.
但那发明家年纪很大了
You see, the inventor was very old.
他临死前  尚未完成一切
He died before he got to fiinish the man he invented.
所以就留下了那个男孩
So the man was left by himself,
未被完成  并且非常孤单
incomplete and all alone.
他有没有名字?
He didn't have a name?
他当然有名字
Of course he had a name.
他叫爱德华
His name was Edward.
雅芳来拜候你
Avon calling!
-你不是刚来过吗? -不  那是上一季了
-Weren't you just here? -No, not since last season!
今天我是来展示新系列眼影
Today I've come to show you our exquisite new line of softer colours, in shadows,
粉底  唇膏
blushes and lipstick.
配合你瞬息万变的容颜
Everything you need to accent and highlight your changing look.
瞬息万变的容貌? 真好
My changing look... That's good!
另外你喜欢的系列我也有
I also have a complete selection of your old favourites,
这是本公司一向畅销的
those tried and true products we've all come to depend on year in and year out.
你知我从未跟你买过
Come on, Peg, I never buy anything from you.
我知道  再见  海伦  再见
I know. Bye, Helen.
这个不用叫我啊
Um, you didn't have to call me, ma'am.
你应该可以自己修理
You could have taken care of this by yourself.
那里可以
I could? I don't think so.
只是水管塞了而已
It's easy. Your food trap's clogged, that's all.
你把这个圆球卸下来
See this bolt here? You just unscrew this...
看
Mm-hm...
这不就下来了吗?
And out she pops.
电视说  水电工都很寂寞
On TV they say you repairmen are a lonely bunch.
其实我们家庭主妇也很寂寞
Housewives get lonely too,
卸下来后
And then you just take this
再小心的装回去
and put it back in here nice and easy. Be careful not to force it.
别使劲  这尺寸刚好塞进  然后再转回去
And then you just screw this back on.
会是谁啊
Oh, now who could that be?
失陪一下
Will you excuse me for a moment?
别乱跑  我马上回来  你教得太出色
Now, don't go anywhere. I'll be right back. This is fascinatin'!
我不想错漏任何一部份
I wouldn't wanna miss a moment of it!
-早  雅芳来拜候你  -为什么
-Good morning, Joyce. Avon calling! -Why, Peg...
你是不是盲的? 看见我这里停了一部车吗?
Have you gone blind? Can't you see that vehicle in my drive?
看见
Oh. Yes.
这就表示现在我很忙
Don't you realise that means I'm busy?
现在我们来选唇膏
OK, now we should decide on lipsticks.
你最喜欢哪一支? 你擦桃红色很迷人
OK, dear, did you like the Winsome Wahini, which looked charming on you,
或者是橙红色
or the Bahimini Bliss?
-我两款都喜欢  -太好了
-I like 'em both. -Well, great!
你不会以为我有钱吧?
You don't actually think I have any money, do you?
叮当  雅芳推销小姐
Ding-dong! The Avon lady!
今天运气真差
Just not my day.
我的天
Oh, my goodness!
好美啊
Oh, it's so beautiful!
哈啰
Hello?
我是雅芳小姐
Hello? Avon calling!
天啊
Oh, my!
有人吗?
Hello?
我是本地雅芳业务代表
I'm Peg Boggs. I'm your local Avon representative. Hello?
很冒昧闯进来
I... I'm sorry to barge in like this,
请不必害怕
but you don't have any reason to be afraid.
这房子真大
Ooh! This is some huge house, isn't it?
还好我参加过有氧舞蹈
Thank goodness for those aerobics... classes.
有人吗?
Hello? Hello?
你为何躲在那里?
Why are you hiding back there?
你不用躲我  我叫碧姬
You don't have to hide from me. I'm Peg Boggs.
我是本地雅芳代表
I'm your local Avon representative,
我像樱桃般可人
and I'm as harmless as cherry pie...
天啊
Oh, my!
我想我一定是打扰你了
I can see that I've disturbed you.
我真笨我立刻便走
How stupid of me. I'll just be going now.
别走
Don't go.
天啊
Oh, my!
你发生什么事?
What happened to you?
-我还没完成  -哦
-I'm not finished. -Ohh!
放下来  请不要再接近
Put those down. Don't come any closer. Please...
这是你的手?
Those are your hands?
这是你的手
Those are your hands!
你怎么了?
What happened to you?
你父母呢?
Where are your parents? Um...
你母亲呢?
Your mother?
你父亲呢?
Your father?
他没有醒来
He didn't wake up.
你一个人吗? 只有你一个人住在这里?
Are you alone? Do you live up here all by yourself?
你的脸怎么了?
What happened to your face?
我不会伤害你
I won't hurt you.
让我为你敷收敛剂
At the very least, let me give you a good astringent.
这可以防止感染细菌
This will help to prevent infection.
你叫什么?
What's your name?
爱德华
Edward.
Edward...
我想你应该跟我回家
I think you should just come home with me.
哦
Ohh!
-不好意思  -不必抱歉
-I'm... I'm sorry. -No. No, don't be.
去看看  你应该会感到很兴奋
You go ahead and look. You have every reason to be excited.
你没事吧?
Oh! You OK?
You OK?
你好
Hello?
我是玛姬
Hi. Yeah, it's Marge.
我刚刚在外面和嘉露聊天
I was standing outside talking to Carol, and Peg drove by.
看见碧姬载了一个男人
She had somebody with her.
-你看清楚是谁? -我没看清楚
-Did you get a good look at him? -No, I didn't.
她家有客人要来吗?
Did she say anything to you about having a guest?
她没说  今早她来按过门铃
Nothing at all. She rang my doorbell at the crack of dawn.
我们待会街角见
No... OK, I'll meet you on the corner.
好  再见
Right. Bye.
妈的
Oh! Damn!
这是我家
Here we go, dear. This is our house.
进来  不要客气
You can just go right in and make yourself right at home, OK?
你要吃  喝什么都行
We'll have something to eat or drink, or... Whatever you...
前门在这儿  我们从这里进去
Here, dear. Here we go. This is the front door. Here we go. Right in here.
乔伊斯  碧姬跟个男人在一起
Joyce? I just saw this strange guy drive in with Peg.
我没看清他什么样子
I didn't get a good look.
只是脸很苍白
He looked kinda pale.
一定要预我参与
On my way. Don't do anything without me.
好  马上到
Yes! Be right there!
就是这里
Here we are.
这是卧室  浴室在后头
So... um, this is the living room and back here are the bedrooms.
你想看照片  好吧
You want to see the pictures? All right.
这是我先生  比尔  他是保龄球冠军
Well, this is my husband Bill. He's a bowling champion.
你知道那是什么吗?
Do you know what bowling is?
保龄球?
Bowling?
这张是在湖边钓鱼
No. Well... Here they are down at the lake, fishing.
凯文看来不太高兴
I think Kevin looks a little glum
因为那天他们一条鱼也没钓到
because they didn't catch anything that day.
这是我女儿嘉莉
And, um... here's my daughter Kim.
盛装参加初中毕业舞会
All dressed for the junior prom.
她现在升上高一了
She's a senior now, ifyou can believe it!
她跟朋友去露营  过几天便回来
She's camping in the mountains with friends,
到时就可以见到她
but she'll be back in a few days. You can meet then.
她很美丽吧?
Isn't she beautiful?
这就是我们全家
That's my family.
来  我带你四处看看
Come along. I'll show you the rest ofthe house.
你去洗个脸  换件衣服
Then you can just freshen up and make yourself at home.
厨房在那边  你想吃什么自己拿
That's the kitchen over there. Help yourself to anything you want.
这是葡萄  后面这是卧室
Those are grapes. And, um... back here are the bedrooms.
我去拿毛巾  还有衣服
Let me get you some towels and I'lI see what we can find for you to wear.
这里应该有比尔的旧衣服
You know what? I think I have some of Bill's old clothes in here.
这件不错
This is perfect!
你应该可以穿
Here. These should just fit you.
-不用怕  -那是电话声
-Oh! Don't be alarmed. That's just the phone.
到嘉莉房间换  我马上来
Now you can go in Kim's room and put these on, and I'll be right with you.
他有剪刀  对
No, no, scissors. No, scissors.
没错  他大概在山上出生吧
That's right. Well, he was... born up there or... something.
-你见过他? -我想他以前没下来过
-Have you seen him before? -No, I doubt he's ever been off the grounds.
那你怎么和他在一起?
Then how did you ever get together with him?
下次再跟你说
Listen, I have to go now. I'll talk to you later, Marge. Bye-bye.
抱歉  我忘了...
Sorry, Edward, I didn't...
我可以帮你吗?
May I help you with this?
谢谢
Thank you.
你划伤了脸
There you go. Oh dear, you've cut your face.
我来替你处理
Here. Let me just get this right off.
-痛吗? -不
-Does that hurt? -No.
好我替你穿衣服
Good. OK. Now, let's get you dressed.
好的
OK...
穿好了  很好
There we go. Very fine!
你穿得很好看
You look fine, just fine!
快我们不等你了
Helen, come on! She wouldn't wait for you.
该死的头发
I've got rollers in my damn hair!
好的
OK...
我的剪刀呢?
Now, what did I do with my sciss...?
爱德华  麻烦你?
Edward, um... would you?
谢谢
Thank you.
我有个医生朋友大概可以帮你
You know, I have a doctor friend who I think could help you.
-真的? -是的
-Really? -Yes.
那些疤我可以想办法
Now, I can help with the scars...
不过  我得先看看雅芳手册
But I just wanna consult the big Avon handbook before doing anything.
凯文
Kevin!
这么看人很不礼貌
It's not polite to stare, dear.
要是人家这么看你  你怎感想
Think how it would make you feel if somebody were staring at you.
-我不在乎  -我在乎  不要再这么看了
-I wouldn't care. -Well, I would, so don't do it!
这对你可是很大的改变
Well, this must be quite a change for you, right, Ed?
-你叫他爱德华好了  -好的
-Edward, dear. I think he prefers Edward. -Oh, sure.
你在上面大房子里做什么?
So what have you been doin' with yourself up there in that big old place?
-我猜景观一定不错  -爱德华
-I bet the view must be spectacular, huh, Ed? -Edward!
嗯?
Yes?
我只是...
No, I... I just...
可以看到海边吧?
See all the way to the ocean, I bet, huh?
有时候可以
Sometimes.
把盐和胡椒递给我
Bill, could I have the salt and pepper, please?
请把盐和胡椒递给我  谢谢
Bill, dear, could I have the salt and pepper, please? Thank you.
凯文
Kevin...!
那东西真型
Man, those things are cool!
一定比剃刀锋利  要是头颈挨这一手刀...
I bet they're razor-sharp. One karate chop to a guy's neck...
凯文
Kevin...!
爱德华
Edward,
你面包要牛油吗?
would you like some butter for your bread?
太棒了
Great!
谢谢
Thank you.
我星期一可以带他上课吗?
Hey, can I bring him to show and tell on Monday?
凯文  够了
Kevin, I've had enough.
你可以睡觉吗?
Do you think you can sleep?
生活起居  你很快会习惯的
I know things feel strange, but soon you'll feel right at home.
-晚安  -晚安
-Good night. -Good night.
先抹些淡色盖斑霜
The light concealing cream goes on first,
然后混在一起
then you blend and blend and blend.
这是秘决
Blending is the secret.
嗯
Mm-hm!
再抹上一点
More concealing cream...
你的五官很好
Your complexion is so fair!
这种霜带点淡紫色的
Now, this has a touch of lavender in it...
这里也抹一点
Give it a try here.
差不多了
Close enough!
很好  这应该可以了
OK, this should do the trick here.
好的
Hmph!
我想到另一主意
I have another idea.
我先把疤痕补平  再开始化妆
We'll cover up the scars and start with a completely smooth surface.
该死的
Darn this stuff!
现在的比分是3比1
They  still  have  11  on  the  scoreboard,  and  it's  three  to  one.
球向华伦的空隙飞去
It's  through  the  gap  to  Warren.
变成12个安打了
Now  they  change  it  to  12  hits.
大声点  我听不见
Turn it up, Kevin, I can't hear it!
凯文
Kevin!
你有没有听见?
Did you hear that, Mr Boggs?
听不见  大声点
No, make it louder!
历史在这一刻被改写
it's  out  of  here,  it's  history
爸
Dad...
你看
Look!
比赛已经进行了5个回合 胜负已分
to  make  ita  fiive-run  inning  and  blow  this  game  to  pieces
乖乖  不得了
I'll be darned.
这么多人打来
They filled the whole tape!
什么回事? 回电
What's going on over there, Peg? Call me.
我是玛姬  他是谁? 回电
Hi, it's Marge. Who is he? Call me.
早上好像下雨
Oh, by the way, lhearit's pouring rain in the mountains.
孩子没事吧?
Do you think the kids are OK?
亲爱的  大家对你的神秘访客有兴趣
Hey there, darlin'! The gals are all in a tizzy about your secret visitor.
你不能老把他藏起来
You can't keep him a secretfor ever!
真是太棒了
Well, it's just wonderful, Ed.
你把全家都修剪出来
My God, you have the whole family in there, don't ya?
他以一记安打回击了那些质疑的声音
And  he  answers  the  challenge  at  first  with  a  strike  of  his  own.
爱德华  你来
Edward, come here.
孩子  这样不对
No, no, no, that's a terrible idea, son!
去车库拿点油来  我们可不能让它生锈
Go to the garage and get the oiI can. We don't want him rusting up on us.
哦
Ohh!
爱德华  这是你剪的?
Edward, you did us!
-比尔  那是我们啊  -是的
-Oh, Bill, it's us! -Yes, it is.
哦  爱德华
Oh, Edward!
他非来自天堂  而是来自地狱
It's not heaven he's from, it's straight from the stinking flames of hell.
我感觉得出他有魔鬼法力
The power of Satan is in him, I can feel it.
-你们有绵羊走失吗? -我们不是绵羊
-Can't you? Have you sheep strayed so far? -We're not sheep.
别靠近我
Don't come near me.
对  你走开吧
That's right. Go on, get outta here, run!
爱德华  你别听她的
Edward, don't you listen to her!
别理她  她是个疯子
Don't worry about her, Edward. She's just a little loony, that's all.
嗨
Hi!
你们就像寄居蟹全躲起来
You-all are hidin' in there like hermit crabs.
乔伊斯
Hi, Joyce. Hi!
真不该  把好客人据为己有
Shame on you, keepin' your unusual guest to yourself.
你太自私了
We think that's mighty selfish of you.
我们确是有点兴奋
Things have been hectic here.
很不错  你愿意改善
That is so sweet of you to wanna correct the situation.
什么时候举行BBQ?
What time does the barbecue begin?
BBQ?
Barbecue?
不把你客人跟大家介绍吗?
You intend to introduce your guest to your friends,
-不吗? -我带凉拌卷心菜
-don't you? -I'll bring coleslaw.
我带神仙沙拉
And I will bring the ambrosia salad!
-你说几点开始? -几点啊?
-What time was it that you said? -Uh, what time...
-比尔  -五点好了
-Bill! -About five?
比尔
Bill!
他是头一个被派来诱惑你们的
He has been sent first to tempt you!
但现在还来得及  你们必须把他赶走
But it's not too late. You must push him from you, expel him.
毁灭这个怪胎
Trample down the perversion of nature.
你们听到吗? 他是怪胎
Did you hear that? He's a perversion of nature.
这真是太刺激了
Why, isn't that excitin'?
-再见  -谢谢
-Bye-bye. -Thanks so much.
比尔
Bill! Bill?
这种BBQ  是绝对少不了卤蛋的
You really can't have a picnic or a barbecue without devilled eggs.
这是最好吃的
They're just... the best. They make a thing.
哦  爱德华  不知你已切了这么多
Oh, Edward, that's wonderful! I didn't know you'd chopped the whole thing.
吃不了那么多
We're gonna be...
我们只需要一点点
Oh. All right now, it's just a nick.
你不必那么紧张
There's no need to be nervous, dear.
又不是要来很多人
Esmeralda won't be here.
邻居们都是很和蔼可亲的
And the rest of the neighbours, they're really very nice.
你不必紧张  他们好想见你
There's no need to be nervous. They're so eager to meet you!
你自然点就行
You just have to be yourself.
-自然点? -是的  原来可爱的你
-Myself? -That's right. Just your own sweet self.
-谢谢  -跟我们玩包剪槌吧
-Thanks, Edward. -Hey! Play scissors, paper, stone with us.
玩什么?
Play scissors what?
我有个医生朋友也许可帮你
I got a doctor friend might be able to help you.
-他手脚真的那么俐落  -才一下午功夫?
-He did them just like that! -That is incredible.
-米高  你好吗? -你好  杰克
-Hi, Mike, how you doin'? -Hello, Jack.
孩子们
Hey, kids!
你好  我是佐治  你握手不大方便吧
Hi, George Monroe. That's a heck of a handshake you got there, Ed.
亨利  上礼拜你在高尔夫球场
Harry! I saw you on the golf course last week...
你还好吧? 要吃什么? 你饿了吗?
Are you OK? Do you want something to eat? Are you hungry?
要饼干吗?
Do you want a cracker?
-他好怪异  -和其他人完全不同
-He's different. -Completely different.
没错
No kidding.
-他好...  -神秘?
-He's so... -Mysterious.
是的
Yeah.
你看他的手是冷或热的?
D'you imagine those hands are hot or cold?
你瞧那剪子能做什么?
And just think what a single snip could do.
解开裤带呢?
Or undo.
爱德华
Eddie. Eddie.
星期五晚  过来跟我们打牌吧
The guys and I want to invite you to our card game Friday night.
你要来吗?
Would you like that?
只有一个要求  你不能切牌
Only thing is... you can't cut!
我也有个残障地方  对我一点妨碍也没有
I have my own infirmity. Never did me a bit of harm.
战时受的伤  使我没了知觉  一点知觉也没有
Took some shrapnel during the war, and ever since then I can't feel a thing!
别让人说你是残废
Don't you ever let anybody tell you you have a handicap.
谁残废了? 我的天
Who's handicapped? My goodness.
不要说笑  你才不是残废  你...怎么说?
Don't be ridiculous! You're not handicapped, you're...
你是万中无一
What do they call the... exceptional?
我是乔伊斯
My name's Joyce,
你还没尝神仙沙拉
and I noticed that you have not tasted any ofthe ambrosia salad...
那是我特别为你做的
that I made especially for you.
让我来喂你
Allow me.
嗯
Mmm!
Mmmm!
-来尝尝这个  我妈调制的  -你修剪功夫棒极了
-You must try this. It's my mother's recipe. -Doesn't this look gorgeous?
到我家帮个忙吧
With a green thumb like yours, I sure could use your help at my place.
帮我剪一组天使
I want a row of angels!
抱歉
I am so sorry, ladies,
他答应先到我家
but he's promised to come to my house first. Haven't you, Eddie?
-你答应过的  -大家注意
-I did? -OK, everybody, grab your plates!
汤来了  准备盘子
Soup's on!
Azhuzhizha zhizhgab
Azhuzhizha zhigabab.
-什么? -我thuzhizha zhizhgabab
-What? -I thuzhizha zhizhgabab.
的确是
It is shish kebab. It was a figure of speech.
但要了解别人说话背后含意
You shouldn't take things so literally.
假设我们在客厅  女主人招待茶
Let us pretend we are in the drawing room and the hostess is serving tea.
我们面对许多问题
Many numerous little questions confront us.
接茶时  应站起来吗?
Should the man rise when he accepts his cup oftea?
可以用剪刀手拿糖吗?
May lump sugar be taken with the fingers?
不
No.
再接受第二杯茶合适吗?
Is it good form to accept a second cup?
餐巾应完全打开呢?
Should the napkin be entirely unfolded...
还是应保留中间折痕?
or should the centre crease be allowed to remain?
我们难免会犯尴尬的错误
It is so easy to commit embarrassing blunders,
但礼仪能使我们知所进退
but etiquette tells us just what is expected of us...
避免陷入狼狈失礼及不安中
and guards us from all humiliation and discomfort.
真的很闷吧
Mm, yes. Boring.
我们改看一些...
Let us switch to, uh...
诗
to some poetry, hm?
有位来自好望角的老人
There was an old man from the Cape,
他做了件皱纱大衣
Who made himseIf garments of crepe.
有人问大衣会破吗?
When asked: Will they tear?
他说已经破了
He replied: Here and there,
但反而好看
But they keep such a beautiful shape!
对了
That's right.
笑吧很有趣的
Go ahead, smile. It's funny.
好
That's right.
到了
We're home.
该死
Shit.
全身都是臭汗
Everything's still sopping.
-我等不及要洗个澡  -还有睡回在床上
-I can hardly wait to take a shower. -And to sleep in a bed.
我家防盗系统已开  只好睡外面
If my parents have the alarm set, I'm screwed.
我不是叫你先打电话回家
I told you to call them and tell them we're coming back early.
-那你自己有没有? -他就是喜欢抱怨
-But did you? -Nope, he'd rather complain.
为什么永远都针对我?
How else am I supposed to get attention?
-你有否打电话回家? -我们家没那么紧张
-You didn't call your parents. -They don't run things like a police state.
-再见  谢谢送我一程  -再见
-Bye. Thanks for driving, Denny. -Bye.
-再见  -再见
-Bye. -Bye.
-别忘了你的胳膊  -是的
-Don't forget your arm! -Oh, yeah.
走吧
Come on, Jim, let's go.
我房间里有人
There's somebody in my room! Go look! Look!
他手上有斧头  他想杀我
He's a murderer! He's got an axe! He tried to kill me!
-一起都好  -妈妈  去看看
-Everything's OK. -Mom, go look!
没事回去睡
Go back to bed, Kevin.
这边
This way.
你说什么? 爱德华住在我们这里  没什么好担心的
Edward's come to live with us. There is nothing to be upset about.
不  没事了  我马上替你弄床铺
OK. We'lI have you set up here in a minute.
我们这里有张特大号的床
We got a full queen-size bed here, believe it or not.
什么都齐备
Oh, it's all made and everything. Good.
好了
There you go.
怎么了?
What's the matter? What's wrong?
她令你紧张吗?
She get you nervous?
你在那个城堡独居太久了
You've been cloistered away up in that castle too long.
对少女一点概念也没有  她们最疯狂了
You don't know about the wonderful world of teenage girls. They're all crazy.
-这能令你镇定一点  -这是什么?
-Here, this'll straighten you right out. -What is it?
柠檬汁
Lemonade.
我也不懂她们
I don't know what it is.
女孩到了某个年纪
They reach a certain age...
荷尔蒙使身体发胀
They develop these gland things, their bodies swell up...
于是便疯狂起来了
They go crazy.
荷尔蒙?
Glands?
是的  荷尔蒙
Yeah, glands.
我尽量不想这些事
I try not to think about it.
好东西  对吧?
Good, isn't it?
你先睡在凯文房
Now, you stay in Kevin's room tonight
明天再整理你的房间
and tomorrow we'll fix your room right up.
你为何带他来这里
Why did you have to bring him here?
要是你也会这么做
I couldn't have left him all alone. You'd have done the same.
为什么他要住这里
Why does he have to stay here?
天  他不像你啊  他天生如此
My goodness, Kim, I'm surprised at you. He can't help the way he is.
-有点同情心吧  -我有同情心啊
-Have a little sympathy. -I do have sympathy.
你来跟人家打个招呼  握握手
Then say a little greeting. Come downstairs, shake the man's hand...
-跟他握手? -不是字面的意思
-Shake his hand?! -Well, not literally.
-你吓到他了  -我吓了他吗?
-Goodness, you scared him half to death! -I scared him to death?
我跟你们正式介绍
Hi, Bill! I just wanted you two to have a proper introduction.
这位是我们的女儿...嘉莉
Edward, this is our daughter Kim.
爱德华他跟我们一起住
Kim, this is Edward, who's gonna live with us.
嗨
Hi.
呵...
H-h-h... H-h-h...
Eddie
Eddie!
渴了吗?
Thirsty?
安静点
Kisses! Hush up!
别吵
Shh, quiet now!
你让我无法思考  你是妈妈的宝贝女儿
Darlin', I can hardly hear myself think! Momma's precious little baby girl...
你要不要冰凉的柠檬汁?
Aah! Wouldn't you like a nice cool glass of lemonade?
柠檬汁?
Lemonade?
向头颈这么一劈他就完了
One chop to a guy's neck, and it's all over.
他的剪刀锐利无比  什么都削得断
Sharpest things in the world. They can hack through anything.
还有...
And...
我觉得这东西很奇怪
They give me the creeps.
你该看他在彼太太院子剪的那个
You should see the clown in Miss Peters' yard.
嘉莉
Kim!
-不  -就是他吗?
-Oh, no. -That's him?
-嘉莉  他在叫你  -够了
-He's calling you, Kimba. -Stop it!
爱德华  你忘了拿你的饼
Edward, you forgot your cookies.
别怕  她在等你
Don't worry, Eddie. She's waiting for ya!
-够了  -我们走
-Stop! -Let's go.
你知爱德华在积奇处吃午饭
Bill, Edward had lunch at Jackie's today...
她装修了厨房
and she just had her kitchen completely redone.
-我弄得  -新油漆  新瓷盘  新地板
-I'll be darned. -New paint, new cabinets, new floors,
-新微波炉  洗碗机  -太棒了
-a new microwave, new silent dishwasher... -Isn't that wonderful?
占美  你妈把厨房也装修过
Jim, didn't you just tell me your mom had her kitchen done too?
是呀  我老爸新添了一些家电
Yeah, my dad bought himself a bunch of new toys.
宽银幕电视  CD  四头录影机
Big-screen TV, CD players, VCR with four heads...
天  有钱人就是会享受
My goodness sake! I wonder what it's like to be that rich.
这些东西都上了锁
They keep things locked up.
我爸不准我碰
My father has his own room for his stuff to make sure I can't use it.
他很吝啬甚至不替我买车子
He won't even help me buy an old car.
他要你自食其力  养成独立
He probably wants you to pay for it yourself. It builds character.
以后你会更感激他
You'll appreciate it more.
谈到钱...
Dad...!
爱德华  提到钱
Speaking of money...
我知道你剪草都不收钱...
I understand you're not charging for your gardening, Edward.
不  比尔  玛姬做了些饼  给他
Now, Bill... Marge made him cookies today.
亲爱的...
Sweetheart...
你不能拿饼  去买东西...
You can't buy the necessities of life with cookies.
饼干买不到车子  对吧?占美
You can't buy a car with cookies. Am I right, Jim?
是的
Uh, that's true, sir, you can't.
我不敢吃  他的手碰过
I... I can't eat that. He used his hands.
我觉得不卫生
It's... I don't think it's sanitary.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我替你把衣服弄干净
Honey, you want me to help you clean that up?
不用了
No, that's OK.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
这是我的爱丽丝吗?
Alexis? Oh, this can't possibly be my Alexis!
她看起来美极了  看看你
She looks so beautiful! Look at you! Sweetie!
好漂亮谢谢
She's gorgeous. Thank you!
等一会  他在决定发式
It won't be long. She just has to decide on the style.
然后就好了
And then it'll be fine.
让它看起来大一点  就像我的头发一样
I was hopin' for somethin' big and kinda bouffant. Kinda like mine?
小狗狗  别怕
Now don't you worry, Kisses, you're gonna be just fine.
你会变得好漂亮的
You're gonna be so pretty.
是的
Yes, you are. Oh!
哦  天啊
Oh! My!
哦
Oh! Ohh!
爱德华  你没有不会剪的吧?
Oh! Eddie, is there anything you can't do?
真是叹为观止
You take my very breath away, I swear. Look at this!
你替女人剪过发吗?
Have you ever cut a woman's hair?
来替我剪吧
Would you cut mine?
这是我一生中最难忘的经历
That was the single most thrillin' experience of my whole life.
连总裁都知道了
They're getting the head of the company!
-我回来了  -亲爱的  我们在这里
-I'm home! -Hi, honey. We're in here.
-嗨  -嗨
-Hi. -Hi!
你把头发怎么了?
What did you do to your hair?
爱德华剪的  很野吧
Edward cut it. Isn't it wild?
真不敢相信能亲自和你说话
Hello? Oh, I can't believe I'm talking to you in person.
真是好荣幸
This is such an honour.
他就在这里
Yes. He's right here.
那你都清楚知道了
So then you know all about it.
我正是用那种敷料
Uh-huh. Well, that's exactly what I've been using.
我在调教份量上有一点问题
Well, I've had a little trouble getting it the right consistency...
只是一点
well, just a little.
我会试试看
I'll try that. Uh-huh.
你这建议真好
Well, what imaginative suggestions.
我会的  多谢您
I sure will. Thank you so much. Bye-bye.
难怪人家是做总裁的
No wonder she's the head of the company.
她原先也只是个业务代表
You know, she started out as a sales representative just like me.
我一直就想跟她谈谈
I've always wanted to talk to her, but until now I never had a reason.
谢谢你  爱德华
Thanks, Edward.
-她有好主意? -她当然有
-She had some ideas? -You bet she did.
-哦  -嗯
-Uh-huh! -Mm-hm!
我来开
I'll get that.
爱德华  我们到了
Edward. We're here.
把剪子磨利点吧
Come on, let's get you sharpened up.
-有吗? -我真不敢相信
-You got it? -No. I can't believe this.
这真是个好剪刀
This is such a drag.
嗨
Hi!
-再见  -再见
-Bye. -Bye.
你有钥匙吗?
Do you have a key?
没有
No.
-我发誓他们都在我的包里  -我们进退两难了
-I could have sworn they were in my purse. -Well, we're stranded.
谢谢
Wow! Thanks!
干得好  你没把门锁弄坏吧
Ed! What a guy! Good job. You didn't break it or scratch it or anything.
碧姬回来就通知我们
Hey, be a pal and yell when Peg pulls in, huh?
真是离奇的故事  有没有人要发问?
Quite a story, yes? Any questions for Edward?
借过
Yeah? Get away over.
请起立
Stand right up.
新生活中你最喜欢的是什么?
What's been the best part of your new life here in town?
交到的朋友
The friends I've made.
其它问题?
Any other questions?
你想过做整容手术吗?
Have you ever thought of having corrective surgery or prosthetics?
我认识有位医生可帮你
I know a doctor that might be able to help you.
我愿意跟他碰头
I'd like to meet him.
名字我们待会再说  谢谢
We'll get that name after the show. Thank you. That's very nice.
还有谁要发问? 若你的手是正常的
Anyone else? Yes, stand right up.
你就会跟普通人一样
But then you'd be like everyone else.
我知道
Yes, I know.
他会喜欢的
I think he'd like that.
没有人会再觉得你很特殊
But then no one would think you were special.
你也不会再上电视
You wouldn't be on TV or anything.
无论如何  爱德华都是特殊的
No matter what, Edward will always be special.
还有问题吗? 请起立
More questions? Yes. Stand right up.
你的手艺相当特别
Your work is so interesting, distinctive and unique.
你想不想开家美容院呢?
Do you have any plans to open your own beauty salon?
这是个好主意
Oh, there's an idea!
还有吗? 请起立
Anyone else? Yeah. Stand right up.
-你有女朋友吗? -哦
-Do you have a girlfriend? -Ohhhh!
他有的  对吧?嘉莉
Sure he does. Right, Kim?
-是吧? 嘉莉? -你又让他来难为我了
-Right, Kim? -Great! Now you got him started.
别吵
Knock it off, bubble-butt.
-是你先挑起的  -那怎么样?
-You did it. -So?
你心中有没有心仪的女孩?
How aboutit, Edward? ls there some speciallady in yourlife?
哦
Ooh...
没事的
Uh... everything's all right.
广告后我们再来
We'll take a break and we'll be back after these messages.
笑什么? 他受伤了
Why are you laughing? He got hurt!
-只是电击一下  -电击一下?
-It was just a little shock. What do you care? -A little shock?!
我倒想录下来  再看一遍
I wish we'd been taping that. I'd give my left nut to see that again.
你难道不兴奋吗?
Aren't you excited? This is so thrillin'!
我们这一家美容院
Wait till I show it to you. It's just perfect.
实在太棒
It's just what we've been lookin' for.
我想取名为"剪发乐园"
I wanna call it Shear Heaven!
我们到了
Ohh! And here we are.
这里摆一排的镜子
Now, all along here I'm gonna put a row of new mirrors.
后面呢...
And back along here, well, I think...
来吧
Eddie! Come along, doll.
这边是一系列的化妆品  一整排都是
Back up here a whole row of new cosmetics. And all along this row here...
-碧姬可以在这里售货  -对啊
-Peg could sell cosmetics. -Yeah... Sure.
洗头的地方在此
And this of course is where we wash the hair.
我便在这里招呼客人
And here is where I stand... when I greet the customers.
后面才是我最要跟你介绍的
But back in here is what I really wanna show you.
爱德华  这才是我要给你看的
Eddie... This is what I really want to show you.
这是我们的贮藏室
Now, this is the storeroom where we keep everything,
每天我需要你替我作个决定
and what I need from you today is a decision I need you to help me make.
不  那很危险
Oh, honey, no! No, don't. That's dangerous.
你坐在这里
Now, you just sit right down there...
我有件工作服  我来为你示范好吗?
I have some smocks. Would you like me to model them for you?
好的
Yes.
OK.
这是我最喜爱的一件
Now, this is my favourite.
因为是黄色的
Because it's yellow...
它的作用是...
And what it's for...
可以阻止头发掉下来
is to catch those itchy little trimmings that fall down your neck.
还有一件是紫色的
And then there's this old purple one that you just kinda...
就是只有一片盖在上面
drape around you like this.
我喜欢这一件
I like that one.
你为什么在发抖
Why, Eddie, you're tremblin'.
我也是
So am I!
我已期待这一刻好久了
I've been waitin' for this moment for so long.
爱德华
Edward!
回来  你不能这样便走了
Edward, you come back here! You can't do that!
魔术贴
Velcro, sweetheart.
-就是仪表板上用的双面夹  -我从未见过
-It hangs on the dashboard. -I've never seen that.
-对不起  我来迟了  -嗨  爱德华
-Sorry I'm late. -Hi, Edward.
对不起  我们吃起来了
Sorry, dear, we had to go ahead without you. There you go.
今天工作情形如何?
So, Edward, did you have a productive day?
马太带我去看美容院的地点
Mrs Monroe showed me where the salon will be.
-你会有个化妆专柜  -不好吗
-You could have a cosmetics counter. -Wouldn't that be great?
真棒
Great.
她带我到贮藏室  然后脱去衣服
Then she showed me the back room where she took all her clothes off.
听你这么说  我很高兴
Edward, I can't tell you how thrilled I am. I'm as pleased as punch.
你在美容院可学到不少
This venture's gonna teach you volumes.
还是经营自己的事业好
There's nothin' like running your own business.
听你这么一说
I've never done it myself,
你的工作真是令人满意
but I gather it's the greatest satisfaction a working man can have.
接下来  你就要跟银行打交道
So I guess the bank's gonna be your next step, huh?
银行?
The bank?
去贷款  准备起步
Yeah. Take out a loan, get yourself started.
凭你的功夫  很快便可闯出名堂
Nothin' to worry about. With your talent and reputation, it's gonna be a snap.
是啊
Yeah.
没有银行记录
No credit,
没有往来记录  亦无工作记录
no record of jobs you've held,
没有存款
no savings,
与私人投资
no personal investments...
没保险号码  你根本就不存在
No social security number you may as well not even exist...
-没有抵押品  -我们的房子已抵押
-There is no collateral. -No, we already have a second on the house.
法院的证词可以吧
But don't the testimonials count?
市长太太都要来请他剪发
Did you see here the mayor's wife can't wait to become a client?
实在很难办到
We simply can't do it.
你先去办理社会保险号码
Now, get yourself a social security card, establish credit
然后用信用额买车
and buy yourself a car.
你会有很好优待
You have a decided advantage. You can get a handicapped placard...
残障专用车可以任意停车
and park anywhere you like.
简直是欺人太甚
I can't believe it. It's just an outrage.
别担心  无论如何我们会筹钱
But don't you worry. This isn't the end of it. We'll get your money somehow.
-这是违法擅闯呀  -我父母已经买了全保
-But that's breaking and entering. -My parents have insurance up the rear.
下星期  我爸便会全修好
What'll it cost them? A little hassle, that's about it.
-我们不能这样做  -那可以替我们弄到钱
-We can't. -This guy'll give us cash for the stuff.
你不想要车吗?
You don't want us to have our own van where we can be alone?
我们爱去那里都可以?
And a mattress in the back?
你难道不能自己偷吗?
Why can't you do it?
我们需要爱德华来开门
Because the room's locked and we need Edward to get us in.
趁你爸睡时你去拿钥匙呀
Can't you take the key when he's sleeping?
钥匙不在他身边
The only thing he hangs on to tighter is his dick.
嘉莉  他会为你做任何事
-Razor Blades'll do anything for you. -That's not true.
-这话什么意思? 你自己不会去问他  -这样不公平
-Oh, no? Why don't you ask him? -That's not fair.
-没有其它方法呀  -一定有的
-So what? There isn't any other way. -There's gotta be.
我都想过了
Look, I've racked my brain.
你难道不想我们拥有部车
Don't you want us to have our own van?
想呀
Well... yeah.
灯还亮着
Jim, the lights are on!
灯自动会亮  爸妈度周末去了
Those go on automatically. They're gone for the weekend, I told you.
用来防止小偷的
In case of burglars.
-警戒系统你关了吧? -是的  走吧
-You turned off the alarm? -Yes. Let's go.
我讨厌这样
I hate this.
我真不敢相信  他不晓得这是占美的家
Are you sure he doesn't know this is Jim's house?
-他从未来过这里  他去偷过你家? -小声点
-This person stole from you? -Shh! Keep it down!
我告诉过你他去偷过  走吧  走
I told you he stole it, OK? Let's go!
他父母会要他交回吧?
Tell his parents and they'll make him give it back.
我试过  你答应了嘉莉走吧
Listen, I already tried that. Now, you told Kim you'd do this. Let's go.
走
Come on!
快
快...
OK, come on. Come on.
快
Come on, come on, come on! Now! Come on!
我爸里头也安装了防盗
The bastard had it wired separately. Come on!
我们不能丢下他
No, Jim, we can't just leave him here!
-快  -我要这么做
-Come on. -I'm not gonna do this!
-快点  -停下
-Just come on, Kim. -Stop!
放我下来
Put me down!
我们知道你在里面
We know you're in there!
现在取消防盗设定让你出来
We're in the process of deactivating the system so that you can come out!
-丹尼  回去  -不行
-Denny, turn around! -No way.
你不会因误触警铃而被捕
Jim, they can't arrest you for setting off your own alarm.
我会告诉他们我们害怕跑掉了
We'll tell 'em we freaked and ran.
-我不回去  -我们必须回去
-I'm not going back there, OK? -We have to!
我父亲会告我的
No. My father would prosecute.
-他的儿子  -告自己的儿子?
-His own son? -Especially his own son.
是  爱德华说的话我便杀他
And if Edward tells I'll kill him!
-丹尼  回去  -不
-Denny, turn around! -No!
我们一定要回去
You have to!
举起手让我们看见
We want your hands high in the air where we can see them!
举手
Put your hands up!
他手上好像有刀
He's holding something. Looks like knives.
抛下武器
Drop your weapons!
我重覆  抛下武器
I repeat... drop your weapons!
我再警告一次  抛下武器
I'm gonna ask you one more time. This is your last warning. Drop your weapons.
再不服从  我们就开枪  别逼我们开枪
If you fail to do so we'll have to open fire. Don't make us do that, buddy.
抛下武器
Drop your weapons. Drop 'em!
快
Now!
碰到一个神经病的
Looks like we got a psycho.
-预备开枪  -不
-Prepare to fire! -Marge No! No!
-退后  -那是他的手  不是武器
-Stand back, ladies! -Those aren't weapons, those are his hands!
我们认识他
Please. We know him.
锁起来
All right. Cuff him.
-我们可以看他吗? -我们要拘留他观察一晚
-But we can see him now? -We're going to have to hold him overnight.
-他要留下? -明早再带他回去
-He has to stay in prison all night? -You can pick him up in the morning.
爱德华
Oh, Edward!
Hello, Edward.
这都怪我不好
Oh, Edward, dear. I blame myself.
你在打什么主意?
What in God's name was going through your mind, son?
都是我做的坏榜样  我不该羡慕占美家有钱
Why didn't I set a better example? You saw how I envied Jim's parents.
你偷钱做什么呢?
What were you gonna do with that stuff?
我说  我们会替他筹钱开店
I blithely say We'll get money for the salon somehow,
我并不是要你去偷钱
but I never meant stealing.
偷钱是不对的
Dear, stealing's not the way to get it. Stealing's not the way to get anything.
你现在可有麻烦
Uh-uh. Except trouble. And you're in a serious heap of that.
你为什么要这么做呢?
Oh, Edward. Why ever did you do this?
-都是电视片集害的  -那些该死的节目
-Damn those TV programmes! -Damn them all to hell!
是不是有人叫你这样做?
Or did somebody put you up to this?
医生  他没事吧
Will he be OK, doc?
由于长时间的分隔
The years spent in isolation have not given him the tools
他无法分辨是非
to judge right from wrong.
他没有一套遵循的法则
He's had no context. He's been completely without guidance.
至目前为止他的工作  园艺树雕  发型设计
Furthermore his work, the garden sculptures, hairstyles and so forth,
全都显示他
indicate that he's a highly imaginative...
很有创造力
character.
但他对现实却一无所知
His awareness of what we call reality is radically underdeveloped.
放他出去会没事吗?
But will he be all right out there?
他不会有事的
Oh, yeah. He'll be fine.
他们整晚都在担心你
Listen, it could keep me up all night worrying about ya.
你到外面小心点
You watch yourself, you hear?
我听到声音就冲出来
I happened to be up, so I heard all this noise...
我就一直觉得他怪怪的
All along I felt in my gut there was somethin' wrong with him.
-他可能也会挑上我家  -任何一家都可能
-It could have been my house. -Or any of our houses, but...
我不是早警告过你们  他有魔鬼的标记
I warned you, didn't I? I saw the sign of Satan on him.
你们不听我的警告  你们也会看到
You didn't heed my warning, but now you will. Because now you can see it too.
你留在这里
Edward, you stay here.
-你是如何辩白的  -他不想谈
-What do you say in your defence? -Nothing.
-他不想说  -你必须说
-He doesn't want to talk. -You have to say something.
-他现在不能谈  -你是被陷害的吗?
-He can't talk right now. -No comments? No remarks?
你有什么感想?
So, were you set up? What was going through your mind?
我们不想谈
Huh? What do you have to say for yourself?
-就一会  -改天再说
-One comment. One comment. -Later.
看来你在圣诞节以前
Goodness, Lois, it looks like I'lI see you at our Christmas party...
都不会来剪发
before I get you over for your haircut!
今年当然要办舞会
Well, of course we're gonna have it this year.
每年都有办呀
We have it every year. Why wouldn't we?
好的
Well!
你要是这么想那就错了
You may think that, but you're wrong.
你在这里
You're here.
他们没伤害你吧?
They didn't hurt you, did they?
你害怕吗?
Were you scared?
我曾要占美回去  但是他们不听
I tried to make Jim go back, but you can't make Jim do anything.
谢谢你没说出来
Thank you for not telling them that we...
不用客气
You're welcome.
你知道那是占美家一定很难过
It must have been awful when they told you whose house it was.
我早知那是他家
I knew it was Jim's house.
真的?
You... you did?
是的
Yes.
那你为什么还要去?
Well, then why'd you do it?
因为你叫我去
Because you asked me to.
Kimba
Kimba!
Kimmy  嘿
Kimmy! Hey!
不要  你怎么了?
-Don't! -What's the matter with you?
你何时才停止?
When are you gonna stop? I did what I could.
我告诉我爸他是白痴  不然他早坐牢了
My old man thinks he's retarded, so he's free. What more do you want?
-你可以说实话  -你也可以说真话  你也有份
-You could tell the truth. -So could you. You were there too!
-那都是你的主意  我不想做  -你也有份参与
-You know I didn't wanna do it. -But you did do it.
我不知道你干嘛那么在乎
I don't get why you give such a shit anyway.
我们可以重换窗帘和毛巾
Maybe there's a way you can replace the drapes and the towels,
但要对你恢复信心可更难
but our confidence in you is not gonna be so easy to replace.
爸爸
Dad...
教你一点公民道德
OK. A little ethics. You're walkin' down the street.
你在街上捡到一箱钱
You find a suitcase full of money.
附近没有人  你会怎么办?
There's nobody around. No human person is in evidence. What do you do?
你收下这些钱
You keep the money.
你用来买礼物送朋友
You use it to buy gifts for your friends and your loved ones.
你送给穷人
You give it to the poor.
你交给警方
You turn it in to the police.
-爸  这太愚蠢了  -金
-Dad, this is really stupid. -Kim...!
-我会收下  -安静
-I'd keep the money. -Simmer down.
爱德华
Edward?
吃完饭  我们去打保龄球吧
Hey, how about after dinner we go down to the bowling alley? That'd be fun.
你今晚不去找占美?
You're not seeing Jim tonight?
不去
No.
今天的课棒极了
We had the coolest show and tell today.
有个同学带来了小袋鼠  全身光溜溜的
This kid brought in a box of baby possums. Ten, maybe twelve. Totally naked.
-凯文  -我想你爸还没说完话
-No hair at all. -Honey, your father isn't finished yet.
谢谢  爱德华我们在等你回答
Thank you, dear. Edward, we're waiting.
送给我的好朋友
Give it to my loved ones?
你觉得该这么做  但这不对
Oh, Edward, it does seem that that's what you should do, but it's not.
白痴呀  应该交给警方才是
You dope, everybody knows you're supposed to give it to the police.
凯文  你说得对
Good thinking, Kevin.
你们大家想一下
Well, think about it, you guys.
他这么做也很好
I mean, that's the nicer thing to do. That's what l would do.
我们要让他能够了解现实
We're not trying to confuse him, we're trying to make things easier,
大家别再闹了
so cut the comedy.
我觉得这样做可爱多了
I am being serious, Dad. It's a much nicer thing to do.
我们现在是要教他明辨是非
Forget nice. We're talking right and wrong.
别笑
Shut up!
难怪爱德华学不好
Oh, goodness! No wonder poor Edward can't learn right from wrong,
住在我们这样的家庭
living in this family!
你知他将碧姬家怎么了?
Well, did you hear what he did to Peg's curtains?
他们还打算开圣诞舞会? 你要去吗?
It's unbelievable they're having their party anyway. Are you going?
我不想去
I don't think so.
其实他强暴了乔伊斯
He practically raped Joyce, threatening her with those knives.
用他的剪刀来威胁她就范
It's a miracle she escaped.
我不是怪比尔和碧姬
I have nothing against Bill and Peg, but...
但是他们家有一个未成年少女
I know. They've got that teenage daughter in the house.
可怜的孩子  我这么一出事后
Those poor things! After what happened to me...
你能想像吗?
Can you imagine?
你说他们要办舞会?
What did you say about the Christmas party?
我说我可能会去
I said I hoped we could make it.
我也撒了同样的谎
I lied too.
你要替我剪新发型吗?
Edward? Do you want to give me that new haircut?
-还要吗? -是的
-Again? -Yeah, sure!
我很荣幸有你这位个人发型师
It makes me proud to have you as my own personal hairdresser.
-嗨  亲爱的  -嗨
-Hi, honey. -Hi.
-你要不要玩包剪槌? -不
-Kevin, want to play scissors, paper, stone? -No.
-为什么  -无聊死了我老是赢  我出去了
-Why? -It's boring. I'm tired of always winning.
-我要出去-你礼貌点
-I'll be outside -A few manners!
你不要介意  你剪吧
Never you mind, dear. Just... cut away. Cut away.
还要多添点什么呢?
It needs something... else. What do you think, honey?
-小钟? -再加小钟  好的
-More bells? -More bells. OK.
妈  我们真要开舞会吗?
Mom, do you really think we should be having this party?
当然是要办呀
Of course I think we should be having this party.
这样可让事情平静下来
It's just what we need to calm things down,
让一切回复正常
and... everything'll go back to normal. Hm?
你还有小钟吗?
Do you have any more bells, honey?
嘿
Hey!
看你做了什么
Now you've done it.
只是划了一道  没事的
It's just a scratch, Jim, really. It's OK.
-再碰她我就要你的命  -这没什么大不了的
-Touch her again and I'll kill ya. -It's no big deal.
-快叫医生  -不
-Call a doctor. He skewered Kim. -No!
远离她  我说真的
Stay away from her. I mean it!
你到处惹祸
You can't touch anything without ruining it.
你为何还待在这里?
Why do you hang around here anyway?
你坐下来  我去拿冰块来敷
I want you to sit right down and wait for me to bring you some ice.
我马上回来
Stay right there. I'll be right back.
圣诞的清晨里...
On Christmas day in the morning
滚开
Get the hell outta here!
走  走呀  怪胎
Get the hell out! Go! Freak!
爱德华  你要去哪?
Hey, Edward, where are you goin'?
他人呢?
Where is he?
-他要伤害你  不  -他没有
-He tried to hurt you. -He did not, and you know it.
你疯了吗? 我亲眼看到的
Are you nuts? I just saw him!
占美  我不爱你了  你走吧  走呀
Jim, I don't love you any more. I just want you to go, OK? Just go!
你说真的?
Are you serious?
你因为他离开我
And lose you to that? He isn't even human.
你滚吧
Just get out of here, OK? Just go!
爸  你看见他去那里吗?
Dad, did you see where Edward went?
他沿着街走了下去
I don't know. He just waltzed down the street.
-我们得去找他  -叫你父亲去找他
-We have to find him, Mom. -Your father will find him.
进去  我来处理这事
Go on in the house. I'll take care of it.
我去找他
I'll go find him.
爱德华
Edward!
我要报警
I'm calling the police!
这只是一道小伤口
See all that blood, sweetie? And it's just a little cut.
哦
Oh!
我是来找剪刀手的
Hello. I'm here to see the man with the hands.
哦
Ohh!
-嗯  -他不在  谢谢
-Uh... -He's not here. Thank you.
亲爱的
Oh, dear.
你真的看见他?
Helen, did you actually see him?
是的  你看
Yes! Look!
我是来找剪刀手的
I'm looking for the man with the scissors.
-谢天谢地  你们来了  -他朝那边去了
-Thank God you're here. -He went right down that way, sir.
好  冷静  我们会处理的
All right, calm down, calm down. Go on home. We'll handle it.
回家去
Just go home.
-他是恶魔  -抓住他一定要抓住他
-A... a demon. A demon. -You gotta do somethin'!
你爸一定会找到他
I'm sure your father'll find him soon.
几点了?
What time is it?
八点半了  今天派对可真棒呀
It's almost 8.30. Great party, huh?
他们去了哪里?
Mom, where are they?
-天啊  -希望他没事  -我也希望
-God, I hope he's OK. -So do I, honey.
当我把爱德华带回家
You know, when I brought Edward down here to live with us,
我实在没好好考虑清楚
I really didn't think things through.
也没想到他会发生何事
And I didn't think about what could happen to him.
或者我们会如何? 或对邻居们
Or to us. Or to the neighbourhood.
现在我觉得也许...
And now I think that maybe...
他回去会比较好
it might be best if he goes... back up there.
因为至少他在上面比较安全
Because at least there he's safe.
我们的生活再回复正常
And we'd just... go back to normal.
我几乎走到街尾  都没看见他
I got halfway to the Whitmans'. I didn't see him anywhere.
我们驾车去找他
Let's get in the car and go look for him.
-凯文呢? -他在麦家
-Where's Kevin now? -At Max's.
上帝啊
Oh, for God's sakes!
-你要去那里? -跟你们去
-Where do you think you're goin'? -With you guys.
-你在家等  如果有人来的话  -我们马上回来
-You stay here in case somebody shows up. -We'll be right back, dear.
警察
Police!
爱德华
Edward?
你没事吧?
Are you OK?
没事  你呢?
Yes. Are you OK?
大家都去哪里了?
Where is everybody?
出去找你
Out looking for you.
抱我
Hold me.
我不能
I can't.
我知离圣诞节还很早
I know it's a little early for Christmas, Edward, but...
但我有礼物给你
I have a present for you.
他连她的手都碰不了
Forget holding her hand.
你想他会对她造成什么伤害?
Picture the damage he could do other places.
真呕心
Yeah. That's sick.
我真的快吐了
Ugh! I feel like I'm gonna pass out or puke or something.
等一会  先载我到她家去
Later. First, take me to her house.
占美别叫我开车了
Come on. Don't make me drive.
快开
Just do it!
她真是说得没错
Jesus. Maybe she was right about you.
-快开车  -放松
-Just drive! -Relax!
-明天见  -好的
-See you tomorrow. Call me. -All right.
抓到他了吗?
Have they caught him yet?
-谁? -他  那个残障呀
-Who? -Him! That... that cripple.
抓到了通知我一声
Let me know when they do.
通知大家  好吗?
Let us all know, OK?
做个乖孩子
Like a good boy.
凯文
Kevin.
-Urgh  -你没事吧?
-Urgh! -Are you OK?
-没事  -哦
-It's OK. -Ow!
哦
Ow! Ow!
-爱德华  住手  -我是你的朋友
-Edward, stop! -I'm your friend.
救命
Somebody help us!
你在做什么? 放开他
What are you doing? Get away from him!
嘿
Hey...
-放开我  -什么?
-Let go of me! -What?
凯文
Kevin!
-走开  -爱德华  回家
-Get away! -Edward, come home. Come home!
快逃
Run.
凯文没事  只是划伤
Kevin's all right! It was just the tiniest scratch!
他走了  放他走算了
He's gone. Let's not bother him, all right? Let's just leave him alone.
你快逃吧
Go on, run.
-怎么了? -他死了吗?
-What happened? ls he dead? -Did you get him?
结束了  你们都回家吧
It's all over. Go on home. There's nothing more to see.
都结束了  我要知道答案
What happened out there? I want to know! I want some answers!
一切都结束了
It is all over.
他人呢?
Where is he? Where is he?
回来  我要问清楚
Get back here! I wanna ask you something!
我真不敢相信
Look at that! I don't believe this.
他们没抓到他  我进去
They don't have him. I'm goin'.
这恐怕不好吧
No! That's not a good idea.
他们正来这里吗?
They're coming?
我伤了凯文吗?
Did I hurt Kevin?
他没事  大概是吓到了
No, he's OK. Mostly he was just scared.
我好怕
Edward, I was so afraid.
我还以为你死了
I thought you were dead.
我可没那么想
I didn't.
不
No!
住手
占美  住手
Jim, stop!
不
No!
住手  不然我就自己杀你
Stop it. Or I'll kill you myself.
啊
Aagh!
别再接近她
Hey! I said stay away from her!
再见
Goodbye.
我爱你
I love you.
他在里面吗?
Is he in there?
他死了
He's dead.
屋顶塌下来压死了他
The roof caved in on him.
他们互相残杀
They killed each other.
不信你们可以自己来看
You can see for yourselves.
看到吗?
See?
我要回家了
I'm goin' home.
乔伊斯
Joyce...
她再也没见到他
She never saw him again.
在那一夜之后
Not after that night.
你怎么知道?
How do you know?
因为我也在场
Because I was there.
你还是可以上去看看呀
You could have gone up there. You still could go.
不  亲爱的
No, sweetheart.
我现在已经是个老妇人了
I'm an old woman now.
我只愿他记得我当年的样子
I would rather him remember me the way I was.
你怎知他还活着?
How do you know he's still alive?
我不知道
I... don't know.
不太确定  不过...
Not for sure, but...
我相信他还活着
I believe he is.
在他没下来前
You see, before he came down here...
这里从来不下雪
it never snowed.
之后...
And afterwards...
就开始下雪了
it did.
如果他不在上面  那就不可能会下雪
If he weren't up there now, I don't think it would be snowing.
有时你会见我在雪中翩翩起舞
Sometimes you can still catch me dancing in it.